SHALOO SHALINI

Information Architect, Technical Writer @Arcana Network

Building stuff worth writing about. Writing stuff worth reading.



COORDINATES

+91-9823053661 shaloo.shalini@gmail.com

n_{shaloo}

in shalooshalini

shaloo_shalini

ashalooshalini@shalooshalini

Address: Bunglow 11, Talera Park Kalyani Nagar, Pune MH 411006, India

SKILLS

Docs-as-code
Dev docs, APIs, User Docs
Information Architecture
Onboarding UX
Technical Marketing
Whitepapers, Product Briefs
Blogs
Leads via Docs
AI-enabled Support

WORK SAMPLES

Blog: EIP-7702 Musings
Open Source: GenPipes
Dev Docs: Arcana Network
Marketing: Cloud TL Series

EXPERIENCE

Cryptography/Blockchain
Networking
Cloud, Virtualization
Distributed Data
Management
HPC, Scheduling
Storage, File Systems
Compiler Design
Hand held computing
Enterprise Mail/Calendaring

EDUCATION

Delhi Institute of Tech B.Tech Computer Engg 1993

OVERVIEW

I bridge the customer-product gap. Simplify complex tech through UX, DX focussed dev, user documentation, API docs, product briefs that generate product conversations. Drive crossfunctional value across engineering, sales and marketing. Unique docs-as-code expertise, deep tech, hands on lets me transform product onboarding experience. Reach out for evolved product documentation that is accurate, alive and accessible in rapidly evolving product environments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Information Architect, Docs Engineer Arcana Network — 2022-Present

Streamline complex blockchain technology onboarding by creating comprehensive, user-friendly documentation, including auto-generated API docs, SDK guides, sample code, product collaterals, and technical blogs, while providing critical UX insights and managing GitHub CI/CD doc processes. [Markdown, MkDocs, Docusaurus, GitHub, Netlify, Notion, React, Vite, View]

Technology Marketing, Consultant — 2014-2022

Empowered clients like IDC, IBM, Intel, NetMagic, CacheBox, SignalFX, Pulse Secure (now Ivanti), Evergrid, Veritas, WiteSand, Developerhub.io, and several stealth mode startups with strategic marketing, *competitive analysis, devrel and technical documentation*. I leverage expertise in enterprise SW products, distributed computing, cloud, SaaS, and Al/ML to drive customer-centric technology adoption by simplifying deeply technical concepts to new users. Successfully participated in <u>Google Season of Docs 2019</u> - <u>GenPipes</u> (**Sphinx**) and Numpy (**Hugo**) site content.

VP Technical Marketing, PrimaryIO (Cachebox) — 2013-2014

Developed product strategies, created **marketing collateral**, and leveraged engineering insights to enhance product positioning and market presence in the telecom space in Korea.

Product Manager, Librato (SolarWinds) — 2008-2010

Pioneered developer advocacy, **PoCs**, crafted innovative product strategies, and collaborated with sales and marketing to drive successful product launches in DR, HA, and technical marketing.

SW Architect, Evergrid — 2006-2008

Architected and led HPC IP-based enterprise computing solution (process containers) for DR and server consolidation before VMs were a thing. Launched a new innovative process migration and disaster recovery product while building high-performing engineering teams.

Principal SW Engg, Symantec Research Labs, Veritas — 2003-2006

Demonstrated research-to-project transformation with innovative storage I/O optimization tech by applying SoC simulation techniques to storage analytics, built PoC for P2P distributed FS with NFS/CIFS connectivity.

Engineering Manager, Veritas (Symantec) — 1999-2003

Led the design and delivery of VERITAS Enterprise Administrator platform while scaling engineering team from 6 to 24 developers and driving cross-platform product releases in data management and storage solutions.

SMTS, Cadence Design Labs — 1998-1999

Transitioned from software to hardware engineering by mastering compiler design and SoC development via NC-VHDL while mentoring new team members and implementing early Web 2.0 technologies for knowledge sharing.

SW Engg, Riverrun — 1993-1998

Launched career in mobile R&D by developing enterprise calendaring software and wireless device drivers across multiple platforms, earning recognition with the coveted 'Night in Town' award for exceptional contributions beyond expectations.

AWARDS

Night in town award at Riverrun Software for creativity, innovation, and delivering beyond expectations. TQM Excellence Quality award.

VOLUNTARY SERVICE

<u>CSPathshala:</u> Created educational content to enable computer literacy in underserved schools. Kalyani Nagar Joining Hands Citizens Group: life member, Housing society Treasurer.